Mostafa ghanbari back-end developer

With over 6 years of back-end development experience, I specialize in:

- Technologies: REST-API, SQL, No-SQL, Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, Socket.IO, RxJS, Scrapy, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python,
- Tools: Docker, Linux, Burp Suite, Postman, PM2

I bring a creative and responsible approach to problem-solving and am experienced in Agile methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban. Additionally, I have expertise in Android native development, including MVVM, MVP, Room, Retrofit, Hilt, RxKotlin, Coroutines, and KotlinCompose.



Experience

back-end

Freelance - Full-time (August 2024 - November 2024)

Developing an IoT platform, comprising two Nest.JS projects:

- ControlPanel: Developed a **RESTful** API for managing things, Applets, **Rules**, Dashboards, Widgets, virtual-things, and advanced access control with default and custom user roles.
- · ControlCenter: Managed MQTT clients authentication, message handling, real-time data provision via socket and data history via RESTful API.
- Technologies: Node.js, Nest.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Socket.IO, EMQX

back-end

Volta Control - Full-time (November 2020 - July 2024)

Built back-end services for IoT & IIoT applications:

- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, Socket.IO, MySQL, Cassandra, Sequelize, JWT, MQTT, UDP, HiveMQ, Mosquito
- Employed Nginx for IP filtering, request limiting, and connection management

back-end

Zaris - Full-time (October 2019 - October 2020)

Contributed to the Ganje (Canso) Start-Up, a search engine for advertising platforms:

- Developed crawlers using Python Scrapy
- Crawled and extracted data from over 10 advertising websites
- Stored extracted data in PostgreSQL

back-end & Android developer

Freelance (August 2018 - October 2019)

- Developed Android application and back-end services for a student services start-up:
 - Features: Chat, blog, advertising, news, professional profiles
 - Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, Socket.IO, Android Studio, Kotlin, ...
- Created a puzzle game using Kotlin, Custom Layouts, Animated Vector, Vector
- Built an app for medical appointment reminders with Alarm Manager, Broadcast Receiver

back-end & Android developer

Mahoor - Intern (August 2017 - August 2018)

Learned foundational programming skills while developing customer service and advertising applications, focusing on:

• PHP, Slim, Java, MySQL, SQLite, REST-API, Android, Android Studio



Address

Iran - Tehran

Phone

+98 915 747 4087

Free time

Climbing, study, music

Email

mostafaghanbari9176@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/MostafaGhanbari9176



Beginner Android - July 2017 Full Stack Developer - January 2018



Education

Sistan And Baluchestan University

Electronic engineering - September 2015

Ferdowsi University

Hardware engineering - September 2020



VSCode, Git, Trello, Taiga, Postman, BurpSuite, Office